[Music]
icici lombard general insurance the
largest
private sector non-life insurance in
india reported a strong profit growth of
in q1 at 521. in our ideas for profit
today i'll delve into what has really
led to the robust performance in q1
that's despite the covet crisis and more
importantly
will it sustain well for sure the
business growth was impacted by kovit 19
and the same is reflected in the gross
direct premium income or gdpi
of the insurer which fell by 5.3 percent
in q1 at 521
that's on a year-on-year basis which was
a tad more than the overall industry
which actually saw the gdpi dipping
by of almost 4.2 percent now on the
other hand it was the lower claims in
the motor business
due to the lockdown that has actually
led to the strong profitability in q1
however this won't sustain as the
situation will reverse in the coming
quarters
and there will be a pickup in the
business but the claims may also climb
up as vehicles have started to fly
across the country now
now in the aftermath of kovid 19
breakout a
number of regulatory relaxations were
extended to the policyholders
for example on april 16 2020 irdai had
announced an extension
extension in the renewal of the third
party motor and health insurance premium
payments
this had led to a short-term impact on
the premium collections
as customers deferred the renewable
renewal premiums as well
now motor insurance which is the largest
segment actually saw the gdpi
plunging by 22 but the property and
casualty segment
grew by 20.5 percent in q1 now the
bigger concern for the general insurance
industry
is the slump in new vehicle sales which
would impact the growth trajectory for
the motor insurance
now management expects fire and health
segments to grow reasonably
but other business lines say marine and
engineering
may witness some degrowth due to the
reduced economic activities
also travel insurance is a big hit for
the company
the insurer also launched a number of
kovit 19 specific
health insurance products during the
quarter retail health indemnity uh
new business was up 26 in q1 of f5 21.
now overall speaking in the near term we
see increased traction in the business
due to the inflow of the deferred
renewal premiums
but after the initial jump in q2 there
may be a slower growth in the premium
in the rest of f521 now in the long term
we see the health insurance business
gaining prominence
and contributing more to the insurer's
premium income
icici lombard's combined ratio that's a
measure of the insurance company's
profitability
uh that is actually reduced to 99.7
percent in q1
when you compare it to 100.4 percent
last year
now the combined ratio of below hundred
percent
indicates that the insurer is receiving
more money from premiums than payouts
in claims and say operating expenses as
well
so that's bit of a good news investment
income in q1 also decreased by 5
and that was mainly due to the lower
capital gains even as the investment
assets
increased now icsa lombard
capitalization remains healthy it is
reflected in the solvency ratio of 250
percent
as at the end of the june quarter now at
the current market price of say
thirteen hundred thirteen hundred
eighteen rupees it is trading at a
premium valuation of nine point
two times the trailing brook which is
quite rich
but being the leader in the company uh
in the sector as well
delivering an roe of say 25 along with
the decent earnings growth as well
the company's uh premium valuations will
sustain even going forward
that said investors need to also
understand the risk underwriting
business is highly volatile
also the insurers profitability is
highly contingent on the investment
performance
external factors like following the
credit rating of the debt holdings or
adverse movement in the equity markets
could actually impair the value of the
investment portfolio
now given the premium valuation the near
time upside in the stock is limited
nevertheless investors with a long-term
horizon and wanting to participate in
the growth in the non-life insurance
sector
can consider buying this talk on dips
going forward